[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[저작권 보호는 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
[Episode 16]
[제16화]
Lei!
뇌 사제
Lifei, you've worked so hard.
소사매, 수고했구나
Only you from Zhuiyu Peak have made it to the top eight.
우리 추옥봉에서는 너만 팔강에 올랐구나
I owe it
그건 다
to you all for cheering me on
우리 사형과 사저들의 격려와 지지 덕분입니다
and our master for training me well.
또한 사부님의 정성스러운 가르침 덕분이지요
Good.
착하다, 착한 제자로구나
All eight competitors tomorrow are formidable.
내일 팔강은 모두 고수들이라
Your opponent, Tang De,
너와 겨룰 당덕은
is the best of Wengu Peak.
문고봉의 수재다
Your little tricks won't work much.
너의 그 술책들은 써먹기 어려울 것이다
True.
맞다
You will lose tomorrow.
소사매는 내일 틀림없이 질 것이다
No point in massaging you.
주물러 줘도 소용없지
He really stops.
바로 그만 주무르네?
Master, teach me some clever moves!
사부님, 제게 기묘한 술법 가르쳐 주시면 안 됩니까?
Last-minute tips won't do much.
이제 와서 벼락치기로 한들 무슨 소용 있겠느냐?
It's good to make it to the top eight.
됐다, 팔강이면 훌륭하다
Go to sleep.
난 자러 간다
But...
그래도
Bedtime now.
자자, 이제 자자꾸나
Go to bed.
잔다
Better try than not.
아무것도 안 하는 것보단 낫지
Nice place!
이곳이 괜찮구나
I'll cram last-minute tips right here.
여기서 빨리 수련해 보자
Who's there?
누구냐?
Are you okay?
괜찮아?
I'm fine.
괜찮아
Go.
가
Did you get hurt picking fruit?
영주과를 딸 때 다친 거 아니야?
Let me check.
나 좀 보자
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge, past the pagoda♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너 부도탑을 지나♪
♪In fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
What are you doing?
아니, 뭐 하는 거야?
♪Betrayed by all, I still♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들♪
You...
너
♪Reign supreme♪
♪어떠하리♪
What are you doing?
이, 이게 무슨 짓이냐고
Let go.
놓아
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪
Lifei!
려비
Don't leave me.
날 떠나지 마
I like you.
난 널 좋아해
I should've ignored you.
역시 걱정하지 말아야 했어
If they find my demonic corruption,
만약 내가 마기에 감염된 사실이 드러나면
I'll be kicked out of Wuyue Court.
반드시 무월정에서 쫓겨날 것이다
I mustn't leave her.
려비를 떠날 수 없어
After searching all sixteen peaks last night,
어젯밤 십육 봉을 철저히 조사하였다
we found up to 11 disciples secretly
무월정에서 마공을 몰래 수련한 자는
practicing demonic arts.
무려 열한 명이나 되었다
They've been expelled with their cultivation crippled.
지금은 모두 수련을 폐하고 선문에서 쫓아내었다
The demon clan tries to split us with evil arts.
마족이 사술로 선문을 분열시키려 한다
This is critical to our court.
이는 생사존망이 걸린 중대한 일이니
Any disciple with a wavering Dao heart
만약 다시 도심이 불순하고
who secretly practices demonic arts for quick power
지름길을 찾아 마공을 몰래 수련하는 자가 있으면
shall be treated as demons and slain without mercy.
마족과 같은 죄로 처형하겠다
He was pretending to be miserable. Hateful!
역시 또 불쌍한 척 연기하는군, 망할 것
Tang De practiced demonic arts,
당덕이 마공을 수련하여
so he is disqualified.
시합 자격을 박탈하다
Jiang Lifei advances straight to the semi-finals.
강려비는 바로 사강에 진출한다
The rest of the top-eight duels go on.
다른 팔강 제자들의 시합은 계속된다
Lifei, amazing!
소사매, 대단하구나
I...
제가...
This is ridiculous.
이건 이치에 어긋나는 일입니다
Isn't the tournament all about real strength?
시합이 실력으로 하는 것이 아닙니까?
Cuixuan, this...
사형, 이...
Don't talk nonsense.
뭐, 뭐, 뭐, 뭐라는 거냐?
Baifu, it's just luck.
백 씨, 이게 바로 운이란 것이다
Accept it and be jealous.
현실을 받아들이고 배나 아파해라
Thank you.
부끄럽다, 부끄럽습니다
My luck won't last long.
보아하니 운이 다한 모양이군
Yue has seniority and strong cultivation,
악 사저는 경력이 깊고 수련이 높으며
plus she's not scared of bugs.
벌레도 두려워하지 않아
I can only try every last trick.
어쩔 수 없이 되는 대로 해 보는 수밖에 없네
Qin?
진 사형
Are you also practicing at Yuelian Pond?
사형도 월련지에서 수련하러 왔어요?
I knew you'd come,
소사매가 이곳에 올 줄 알고
so I waited here for you.
일부러 이곳에서 기다렸다
You want to win the tournament, right?
시합에서 이기고 싶지 않냐?
Since you're in the semi-finals,
이미 사강에 올랐으니
give it your all tomorrow.
내일은 마땅히 힘을 다해야 하지
Are you going to teach me advanced spirit arts?
저에게 고급 술법을 가르쳐 주려는 것입니까?
Hold your breath, and close your eyes.
숨을 고르고 눈을 감아라
Close your eyes.
눈을 감아라
Try to accept me
나를 받아들여 보아라
and merge our spirit energy.
우리 영기가 서로 융합하게
This isn't proper.
이건 좀 아니지요
Don't you want to win?
시합에서 이기고 싶지 않냐?
Merging our spirit energy
나와 영기를 융합하는 것이
is the fastest way to boost your power.
가장 빠르게 공력을 높이는 방법이다
But only cultivation partners do this.
그러나 이는 도려 사이에서만 하는 일입니다
I read about it in storybooks.
이야기책에서 본 적 있어요
Merging spirit energy means
영기 융합은
giving your whole heart and soul.
자신의 모든 몸과 마음을 내놓는 것이라
Only for your beloved.
연인들 사이에만 하는 것입니다
Lifei,
소사매
actually,
사실은...
I have
줄곧
liked you all along.
너를 매우 좋아하였다
Will you be my cultivation partner?
내 도려가 되어 주겠느냐?
Wait.
아닙니다, 사형
I don't feel that way about you.
전 그런 뜻이 없습니다
Is there something wrong with me?
혹시 내가 어디가 부족하냐?
No. You're perfect in every way.
아닙니다, 사형은 모든 면이 훌륭해요
It's me who's unworthy.
제가, 제가 부족해서 그래요
With weak spirit power, I just joined the sect,
영력이 낮고 입문한 지도 시간이 짧아
and I'm not romantic at all, so I'm not the one for you.
또 눈치도 없고, 사형이랑 맞지 않아요
You're overthinking.
지나치게 생각하였구나
I believe we're a perfect match.
난 우리가 매우 잘 맞는다고 생각하는데
I don't think so.
저는 우리가 잘 맞지 않는다고 생각해요
I'm returning this flying ribbon.
이 비릉은 받을 수 없네요
Give it to a stronger,
영력이 더 높고
prettier senior sister instead.
더 아름다운 사저에게 주세요
Lifei, I truly like you.
소사매, 나는 정말 너를 좋아한다
Will you give me a chance?
생각해 보지 않겠느냐?
Let me help you win the tournament first,
혹은 먼저 시합에서 이기게 도와주겠다
alright?
어떠냐?
No need. I want to win,
그건 사양할게요, 이기고 싶기는 하지만
but I'll never act against my heart.
마음에 없는 일은 하지 않을 겁니다
See you.
그럼 이만
Wait.
잠깐만
Who's there?
누구냐?
Lei Xiuyuan.
뇌수원
Qin, what's wrong now?
진 사형, 이번엔 또 무슨 일입니까?
I wanted to chat with her a little longer.
사매랑 말을 좀 더 나누고 싶었을 뿐이다
Stay out of this.
네가 무슨 상관이냐?
Qin,
진 사형
I've said all I need to.
할 말은 다 했습니다
There's nothing more.
더 할 말은 없습니다
Let me send you back.
내가 데려다줄게
No need.
괜찮아
What rotten luck!
이런 화가 일어날 줄이야
My last-minute plan failed again.
또 수련을 못 했고
Lei Xiuyuan, come out!
뇌수원, 나와!
You are too weak to protect yourself,
이 실력으로는 자신을 지키기도 어려운데
yet you trust others blindly.
함부로 남을 믿다니
My worst mistake was trusting you above all else.
내가 가장 잘못 믿은 사람이 바로 너야
You'd better
내일 시합
forfeit tomorrow's duel.
차라리 기권해
Again.
다시 덤벼
You've lost.
너는 이미 졌어
I haven't fallen, so I haven't lost.
내가 쓰러지지 않았으면 진 게 아니야
Again.
다시 덤벼 봐
The fight isn't over yet.
아직 끝나지 않았어!
Chiyan Stone of Xingzheng Hall.
성정관의 적염석이네?
Lifei,
려비
I heard Wuyue Court is holding a tournament.
무월정에서 투법 대회를 연다 들었다
This stone can summon a fire wall
이 적염석은 화염 장벽으로 변할 수 있다
to block a fatal blow. It may help you.
한 번의 공격을 막기에 충분하니 도움이 될 것이다
Thank you, Tongzhou.
고마워요, 동주
Senior Sister, you'll win.
사저는 분명 문제없을 것입니다
Yeah, we believe in you!
- 맞아요 - 사저, 저는 사저를 믿어요
Place your bets!
한 번 걸어 보시오
Lifei, listen to me.
소사매, 내 말을 들어라
First, the Monkey Steals Peach trick.
일단 저놈의 급소를 먼저 공격하거라
Does anyone want to place a bet?
여러분, 한 번 걸어 보겠소?
It'll work.
분명 통할 거다
Do what I said.
내가 말한 대로 해라
That's such a dirty move!
너무 독합니다
Lifei.
소사매
Just do as we said.
우리가 말한 대로 해라
You know what?
내가 말하는데
I cast my fortune today.
내가 오늘 점을 쳐 보았다
It said I'd have great windfall luck.
재운이 특히 좋다 하였고 특히 편재라 하였다
Then I thought and realized
그래서 내가 곰곰이 생각해 보았는데
you're the biggest underdog here.
이 자리에서 가장 편재인 사람이 바로 너다
As the saying goes,
성인이 말씀하시길
the ignorant fears nothing; the shameless prevails.
무지한 자는 두려움이 없고 무뢰한 자는 적이 없다
So
그러므로
I set up
내가 너를 위해
this betting pool
이 도박판을 만들었다
for your duel against Yue.
너와 악 사저의 이 시합을 걸기로 하였다
Anyone want to join?
참여할 의향이 있느냐, 다들
What are the odds?
배율이 어떻게 되오?
One to one if you bet on Yue.
악 사저에 걸면 일 대 일
One to fifty if you bet on Lifei to win.
소사매가 이기면 일 대 오십
Come on.
자
Hey, you there, want to join?
이쪽은 참여할 의향이 없소?
Count me in!
나도 끼워 줘, 나도 끼워 줘
- I'll bet on Yue. - Me too!
- 악 사저에 건다 - 나도 악 사저에 걸겠어
Let me have a look.
저 좀 볼게요
Alright, put them here.
좋다, 여기 두어라
Who're you betting on?
너는 누구에게 거느냐?
- Okay. - Wait.
- 그래 - 아니
Hardly anyone bet on me winning.
제가 이긴다는 것에 건 사람이 이게 다예요?
Don't look down on it.
너무 얕보지 마라
I bet everything on you.
사형은 전부 너에게 걸었다
Fight well, Lifei.
힘내라, 소사매
You're my ticket to wealth!
부자가 되는 건 너에게 달렸다
All bets placed.
됐다, 다 걸었다
Let's watch the duel.
시합을 보자
- Okay. - Go for it!
좋다, 힘내라
- I'm rooting for you, Lifei. - Go for it!
힘내, 소사매, 내가 응원한다
Yue.
악 사저
Lifei,
려비 사매
I won't hold back.
나는 봐주지 않을 거다
Begin.
자
The identical moves.
같은 전법이다
Her zither strings snapped.
거문고 줄이 끊어졌다
- What to do? - What's going on?
- 어찌할꼬 - 이게 무슨 일이냐?
He even taught you the metal technique?
그 사람이 너에게 금지술을 가르쳤느냐?
I'm lost.
내가 졌다
Incredible!
이건 너무 대단하다
Great!
좋다
Well done, Lifei!
소사매, 잘하였다
- Impressive. - Unbelievable win!
- 대단하다 - 훌륭하다, 정말 생각지도 못했어
Let go! Let go of her!
놓아라, 놓아라, 놓아라!
Boy, focus on your duel.
너는 시합에나 집중하여라
You're holding on so tight.
왜 이렇게 꽉 잡느냐
Let's go.
가자, 가자
Lei, I won't hold back.
뇌 사제, 실례하겠다
Lei Xiuyuan is fearless like a new calf.
뇌수원은 하룻강아지가 범 무서운 줄 모르는군
He fought Qin to a draw.
진 사질과 백중세를 이루다니
Promising youth.
앞으로 기대할 만하구나
Cuixuan, you care so deeply for Qin
사형이 진 사질에게 참으로 잘해줍니다
that you even passed down the Yin-Yang Tribulation Mirror to him.
음양겁파경까지 전해주셨다뇨
Lei,
뇌 사제
you're too green.
너는 아직 아직 한참 멀었다
Surrender now, and I'll stop.
만약 지금 항복하면 내가 멈추겠다
Just surrender.
항복하여라
Take my advice:
사제, 충고를 하나 하겠다
The higher you hold your head,
거만하게 굴수록
the harder you'll fall.
나중에 더 큰코다칠 것이다
You're not worthy to beat me.
사형은 아직 나를 이길 자격이 없습니다
Stay away from Jiang Lifei from now on.
앞으로 강려비에게 가까이하지 마십시오
That Longyuan Sword
그 용연검은
was left for you by the former sect leader.
전 장문 사존께서 너에게 남겨주신 것이다
Guangwei,
사제
you truly look out for Lei.
뇌 사질에게 정말 잘하는구나
Great!
좋다
Dragon Roars Across the Sky, the sixth-level art.
용소구천, 이는 제6층의 공법이다
Guangwei,
사형
you've hidden him too well.
이 제자를 너무 깊이 숨긴 것 아닙니까?
This is the real combat.
이것이 바로 진정한 투법이지
Lei Xiuyuan of Yaoguang Peak wins.
요광봉, 뇌수원이 이겼다
Jiang Lifei
한 시진 후
versus Lei Xiuyuan in two hours.
강려비 대 뇌수원의 시합을 시작하겠다
I'm too gravely injured to fight the final.
제가 부상이 심하여 마지막 시합을 할 힘이 없습니다
I will forfeit.
시합을 포기하겠습니다
What?
아니
- Why? - How can he just give up?
- 왜? - 바로 항복하다니?
Yeah.
그러게 말이오
- What's going on? - He fears?
- 이게 뭐냐? - 지레 겁먹은 건가?
I can't understand.
맞아, 이게 무슨 일이야?
Is he forfeiting?
- 기권이네요? - 기권이라니
Does that mean...?
그럼 그게...
- Is that allowed? - I want to ask the same.
- 이래도 된다고? - 그러게
Why?
대체 어째서?
Yue, please help me.
사저, 부탁하겠습니다
Let's go.
가자
You won!
이겼다, 이겼다, 이겼다
- Lifei, you won. - We won!
소사매, 이겼다, 우리가 이겼어
Thanks to you, we're rich now!
고맙다, 소사매, 내가 큰돈 벌었다
We won.
이겼다
- We won! - Great!
- 이겼다 - 좋다
Be careful.
조심하여라
Sit down.
앉아
Let me treat your wounds first.
일단 상처를 치료해 주겠다
You lied. You still have strength left.
사제에게 아직 힘이 있었구나
You let Jiang
이 괴수 자리는
take first place on purpose.
역시 네가 강 사매에게 양보한 것이구나
Thankfully, this was only a duel.
다행히 오늘은 시합일 뿐이다
If it were a life-or-death battle,
만약 생사를 건 싸움이었다면
you'd have sacrificed yourself for her!
그 애를 위해 목숨까지 버렸을 것이냐?
Yeah. It's just a duel anyway.
그러게요, 시합일 뿐이잖아요
Why did you intend to kill her?
사저는 어찌하여 살의를 품으신 거죠?
I...
내가...
If I wanted her dead,
내가 살의를 품었다면
do you think a mere Chiyan Stone
그 작은 적염석 하나가
could stop me?
나를 막을 수 있겠느냐?
Truth is,
그러나
I could kill her anytime.
난 언제든 그 애를 죽일 수 있다
I dare you!
감히?
I told you your talent is unmatched.
내가 전에 말하였지, 너는 타고난 자질이 뛰어나다고
You could become an immortal
선신을 이루든
or a sect leader,
선문의 으뜸이 되든
bound for greatness.
반드시 큰 업적을 이룰 거다
Our master holds high hopes...
사부님도 너에게 기대하시는 바가 있다
My plans are none of your business.
내가 무엇을 할지는 사저와 상관없습니다
You've crossed the line time and again.
사저, 몇 번이고 선을 넘었습니다
What do you want from me?
대체 내게서 무엇을 얻고자 합니까?
What do I want?
내가 무엇을 얻고자 하냐고?
Have you forgotten?
잊었습니까?
I'd lay down my life for you.
저는 당신을 위해 죽을 수 있습니다
My clan's fate rests with My Lord.
전족의 생사가 모두 존상 한 분에게 달렸습니다
I'd die without regret.
신하는 죽어도 한이 없습니다
Whoever you truly are,
사저가 누구든
I joined Wuyue Court for only one person.
무월정에 온 것은 오직 한 사람 때문입니다
Nothing else matters.
다른 것은 상관하지 않으니
Please stay away from me from now on.
앞으로 제게 가까이하지 마세요
Master.
사부님
Well, well.
좋다, 자네는 정말 훌륭하다
You pleaded severe injuries to withdraw,
상처가 중하다 하여 기권하였다니
so I shall indulge your request.
자네가 원하는 대로 해 주겠다
Master.
사부님
You reckless boy! I told you repeatedly
이 못된 놈아, 내가 거듭 당부하였잖느냐
to stand out
무월정 후배 제자들의
among Wuyue Court's young disciples.
으뜸이 되기를 바랐다고
Yet you acted foolishly
한데 너는 한 여자를 위해
and recklessly, all for a girl.
억지 부리고 함부로 날뛰었다
Since you remain stubborn,
말을 안 듣고 고집을 부리니
I'll cripple your spirit root
차라리 너의 영근을 폐하겠다
to stop you from going astray and endangering the sect.
훗날 그릇된 길로 빠져 선문에 해를 끼치지 않도록
Master, he's young and impulsive.
사부님, 사제는 어리고 충동적이었습니다
He merely lost his sense for a while.
잠시 생각이 짧았을 뿐입니다
Please spare him.
사부님, 자비를 베푸소서
I'll guide him well.
제가 사제를 잘 타일러 보겠습니다
Master.
사부님
I'll grant you one last chance.
다시 한 번 기회를 주겠다
I'll show no mercy if you stay obsessed.
만약 또 고집을 부린다면 반드시 용서하지 않겠다
Stand up.
자
Is Jiang Lifei worth all this?
강려비를 위해, 그럴 가치가 있느냐?
Wake up.
정신 차려라
She's your destined tribulation.
그 애는 너의 재앙이다
Conduct yourself wisely.
잘 생각하여라
Enter the Achillea Bead.
시초주를 제사 지내자
I wonder where my master is
사부님이 어디 계시는지 알고 싶습니다
and if he's safe.
안전하신지요?
Wait.
사형
What are you doing?
왜 이러십니까?
The Achillea Bead is a rare treasure.
시초주는 천재지보인데
It dissolved instantly, pouring all its spirit energy into her.
순식간에 형체가 사라지고 영기를 모두 려비에게 주입하였다
That's strange.
참으로 기이한 일이구나
Jiang Lifei must be suspicious.
강려비에게 아마 문제가 있는 듯하다
What's suspicious about it?
이게 무슨 문제가 있겠습니까?
She shares fate with it,
제 제자가 시초주와 인연이 있어서
and it chose to gift her energy freely.
시초주가 더 주려고 하는 거겠죠
What's the problem?
이게 문제가 됩니까?
No such occurrence
수백 년 동안
has happened in centuries.
이런 일은 한 번도 없었다
Luck alone can't explain this.
운이 좋다는 한 마디로 넘어갈 일이 아니다
Cuixuan,
사형
I brought her
강려비는
to Wuyue Court long ago.
그때 제가 무월정으로 오도록 인도하였습니다
She bears a unique, spirit-attracting physique
체질이 특이하여 영혼을 부르는 아이니
that caused
방금 시초주가 이렇게 이변을 보인 것도
the Achillea's strange reaction.
아마도 이 때문일 것입니다
Spirit-attracting?
영혼을 부른다고?
I've been weak since childhood,
저는, 저는 어릴 적부터 몸이 약했습니다
and the spirits always come to me.
그, 그 요령들이 자꾸 저를 괴롭혔습니다
It's not my fault.
저도 일부러 그런 것이 아닙니다
Blame me for this.
이 일은, 나도 잘못이 있다
I'll fetch a protective talisman
자, 내가 지금 바로 너에게
for you right now.
호신부를 하나 만들어 주겠다
Let's go.
가자
The Achillea's chaotic power
시초의 영력은 방대하고 복잡하다
floods Lifei all at once.
려비 사질이 갑자기 너무 많이 흡수하여서
I'm afraid her meridians can't bear it.
경맥이 감당하기 어려울까 두렵다
I'll take you back to Cuihua Peak
내가 지금 너를 취화봉으로 데려가겠다
to stabilize your cultivation.
조금 조리하면 안심할 수 있을 것이다
Don't bother
사형, 이런 일을
with this trivial thing.
어찌 사형께 부탁드리겠습니까?
I can handle this myself.
내가 직접 하겠습니다
The tournament is over,
시초주 대회가 이미 끝났으니
so we'll take our leave.
그럼 우리 먼저 실례하겠습니다
Farewell, everyone!
여러분, 실례하겠습니다
Zhuiyu Peak, go!
추옥봉, 철수하자!
Go.
가자, 가자
Disciples of Zhuiyu Peak, let's go.
추옥봉 사람들, 자, 철수한다
Focus your mind,
신을 모아라
channel energy,
기를 돌려라
and strike once.
한 번 쳐 보아라
This...
이게...
Just as I thought.
역시 그렇군
The thousand-year-old Achillea's
그 천 년이 된 시초의 영기가
spirit energy in your body
너의 몸속에 주입된 후
has boosted your power
영력이 지금 적어도
to at least the fourth level.
이미 제4층에 도달하였다
Am I strong now?
저 그럼 고수가 되었습니까?
Come here.
와 봐
Don't get carried away.
지나친 생각이다
You think more spirit power is something to rejoice in?
영력이 늘어난 것이 좋은 일이라 생각하느냐?
Unregulated surging power will devour you.
잘 이끌지 않으면 오히려 몸을 해칠 우려가 있다
Now you need to practice hard
지금 부지런히 수련하여
to master and integrate it
잘 융합하고 순환시켜야
before you wield it freely.
비로소 자유롭게 사용할 수 있다
Now, understand?
지금, 알겠느냐?
Thought I'd gotten free luck.
하늘에서 떡이 떨어진 줄 알았습니다
This power is too risky to wield.
볼 수만 있고 먹을 수는 없는 거였네요
Lifei, what did you see
려비, 네가 그 환경 속에서
in the illusion?
도대체 무엇을 보았느냐?
Nothing yet
아직 보지 못하였는데
before Elder Cuixuan attacked.
취현 사백이 쳐들어왔습니다
So petty
너무 인색합니다
over a little spirit energy.
영기를 조금밖에 흡수하지 못했습니다
Don't be ungrateful.
너도, 만족하지 못할 게 없다
A little?
이게 조금이냐?
You drained
네가 그 영초를
the spirit plant completely.
털끝까지 빨아들였던데
I felt embarrassed for you.
그때 나도 좀 민망하였다
I didn't mean to.
저도 일부러 그런 것이 아닙니다
Stay
요즘은 얌전히
on the peak lately.
추옥봉 안에 있고
Don't wander off.
함부로 돌아다니지 말아라
And never cross Elder Cuixuan.
명심하여라, 취현 사백을 건드리지 말아라
Master, head back and wait for dinner.
사부님, 돌아가셔서 식사를 기다리십시오
Are you cooking?
네가 하느냐?
Of course.
아니면 누가 하겠습니까?
Off you go.
들어가십시오
Master!
사부님
Ma...
사...
Better check it out,
그래도 한 번 가 보자
or I'll keep worrying.
계속 마음이 불안하네
There's a restriction spell.
금제가 있구나
Come with me.
나를 따라와
Don't act on your own again.
또 함부로 굴지 마
Demonic energy leakage in Lilie Valley.
열렬곡에 마기가 누출되었다
How crafty! Thanks to the demonic energy,
계략 많은 영감탱이, 마기가 있어서 다행이야
or we'd be caught.
아니었으면 들켜서 큰일 날 뻔했어
I haven't asked.
아직 묻지 않았네
What are you doing here?
네가 왜 여기에 있어?
Stalking me?
나를 미행했어?
You just absorbed energy from the Achillea Bead.
네가 방금 시초주를 흡수했으니
I worried you'd feel unwell.
불편할까 걱정돼서
Cuixuan is so upset.
취현이 그렇게 긴장한 걸 보니
There must be a secret hidden on Hushe Peak.
호사봉에 분명 무슨 비밀이 있어
Head back to your peak.
너는 먼저 봉으로 돌아가
Keep quiet.
누구에게도 알리지 말고
Don't alert them.
마족이 눈치채면 안 되니까
Stay out of my business,
내 일에 신경 쓰지 마
understand?
알았어?
For the Vermilion Fruit,
영주과
the tournament,
시초 대회
and what happened today,
그리고 이번도...
thank you.
고마워
I'll remember all of this
내가 다 기억했으니
and repay you someday.
반드시 갚을 거야
Lilie Valley is our sect's forbidden area.
열렬곡은 우리 문파의 금지 구역이다
Sealed jointly by past elders,
전임 장로들이 함께 봉인한 곳이라
it's impenetrable.
철옹성과 같다
It's stayed safe for centuries.
수백 년 동안 무사하였거늘
Why is there demonic energy leakage?
어찌 마기가 외부로 누출되었느냐?
Perhaps the demons trapped inside linger,
아마 그 안에 갇힌 마물이 사라지지 않고
struggling in their last gasp.
발버둥 치고 있는 것일 수도 있지요
The valley lacks spirit energy,
열렬곡 안은 영기가 희박하다
and they've been bound for five centuries.
그것들은 오백 년이나 갇혀 있었으니
Even alive,
죽지 않았다 해도
they're crippled
이미 폐인이 되었을 것이다
and cannot break free.
절대 탈출할 수 없다
Their souls endure centuries of captivity,
수백 년을 갇혀도 신혼이 소멸하지 않았습니다
which means the demonic spirits are far too powerful.
마족 요령이 참말로 강한 것 같으니
We must stay vigilant.
우리는 방심할 수 없습니다
This leakage proves
마기 누출은
the seal
열렬곡 내 봉인이
in the valley is damaged.
훼손되었다는 증거다
First, we must locate and repair
지금의 계책은 먼저 훼손된 곳을 찾아
the damaged areas at once
보수하는 것이다
to stop the demons from escaping.
마물이 곡에서 도망치는 것을 막아야 한다
As Lilie Valley stretches wide,
열렬곡은 넓고 평탄해서
repairing seals drains massive spirit power.
봉인을 보수하는 데 영력이 많이 듭니다
Send elite disciples to search
차라리 정예 제자를 많이 보내어
and guard together.
함께 보수하는 것이 좋겠습니다
Agreed.
맞습니다
The Sea Calamity draws near,
해운이 다가오니
and the demon clan lurks in wait.
마족이 호시탐탐 노리고 있습니다
Young disciples
신세대 제자들은
must learn the true threat of demons
마족이 도대체 무엇인지 미리 알아야 합니다
and gain battle experience,
마족과 교전한 경험을 많이 쌓아야
or more will be tempted
마족에게 현혹되어
to practice demonic arts again.
마공을 수련하는 자가 나오지 않을 겁니다
Fair enough.
좋다
We'll bring
마침 이 기회에
top disciples
시초 대회에서
from the tournament
두각을 나타낸 젊은 제자들도
together.
함께 참여하게 하자
Cuixuan.
사형
Cuixuan,
사형께 아룁니다
my disciple hasn't recovered.
제 제자의 상처가 아직 낫지 않았으니
Zhuiyu Peak will sit this out.
이번에 우리 추옥봉은 참여하지 않겠습니다
My apologies.
송구합니다
Sorry.
송구하네
Our disciples never coddle themselves.
무월정 제자가 어찌 나약하게 자란 자들이겠냐?
She claimed first place.
려비는 일등이다
Her absence would rouse
만약 가지 않는다면
doubt among all.
다른 제자들이 인정하겠느냐?
The enemy draws near.
지금 대적이 코앞에 닥쳤거늘
As cultivators,
우리 수선자들은
we must lead the charge
마땅히 몸소 앞장서야 하지
and never flinch.
전장에서 물러서지 말아야 한다
Elders,
장로들
return to your peaks and gather disciples at once.
각 봉으로 돌아가 즉시 제자들을 소집하거라
We depart in two hours.
한 시진 후에 출발한다
Understood.
예, 사형
Yes.
예
[Lilie Valley]
[열렬곡]
Qin Yangling, Yue Cailing, Deng Xiguang,
진양령, 악채령, 등계광
Elder Chongyi and I will repair the outer seal.
나와 충이 장로는 골 밖에서 봉인을 보수하겠다
You will lead disciples
너희는 여러 제자들을 이끌어
down three separate paths
세 갈래 길로 나누어
deep into the valley
곡 안으로 깊이 들어가
to trace the demonic energy.
마기의 근원을 조사하여라
Me?
제가...
Recapture any escaped demons.
빠져나간 마물을 다시 봉인하리라
Understood.
- 예 - 예
Most demons here have perished,
곡 안의 마물은 대부분 이미 죽었다
yet residual demonic energy lingers for centuries.
하나 수백 년 동안 마기가 흩어지지 않았으니
It's deadly.
매우 위험할 거다
Guard yourselves well
너희가 곡 안으로 들어간 후에는
once inside.
반드시 조심하여라
Do not let the demonic energy
마기가 몸에 침투하지 못하게
corrupt your minds.
심성을 잃지 말게 하여라
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 인간 세상의 부귀영화를 쥐고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이 인연을 맺기가 가장 어렵구나♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈 사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival the lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪수많은 겁난도 향기로운 미련을 이기지 못해♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
♪I trade the highest heaven and endless clouds♪
♪내 구만장천의 붉은 노을을 딛고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Pierced by countless arrows, pain and illness pile on♪
♪만 개의 화살이 심장을 꿰뚫는 고통이 밀려와도♪
♪Yet I remain silent♪
♪그저 묵묵히 소리 없이 삼키네♪
♪Deep love and long yearning, a kiss falls into a dream♪
♪깊어 가는 정과 그리움은 꿈결 속에 내려앉고♪
♪In the distant night, bitterness blooms♪
♪외롭고 긴 밤하늘 아래 쓰라린 꽃이 피어나네♪
♪The grand chapter is rewritten, startling the whole world♪
♪찬란한 운명을 다시 쓰니 온 세상이 경탄하누나♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪얽매인 봉인을 풀 수 없다면 차라리 내려놓으리♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪내 마음 편히 쉴 곳이 곧 나의 집이어라♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds♪
♪비익조가 되어 구름바다를 가로지르고♪
♪Break through the waves; the heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪거친 파도를 깨부수니 마음의 바다는 끝이 없어라♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪언제나 가혹한 숙명의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water and falling petals♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과 지는 꽃 같으니♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪